* Worldwide

* Austria

* Belgium

* Bulgaria

* Czech Republic

* France

* Germany

* Iceland

* Italy

* Marché International

* Netherlands

* North America

* Pacific

* Poland

* Romania

* Singapore

* Spain & Portugal

* Switzerland

* UK & Ireland

* United Arab Emirates

*   Worldwide     [En](https://www.lagardere-tr.com/en) | [Fr](https://www.lagardere-tr.com/fr)

Search 

Privacy Policy
==============

**1\. Identity and contact details of the Data Controller**

The website www.lagardere-tr.com is managed by Lagardère Travel Retail SAS with registered headoffice at 3/9 avenue André Malraux, 92300 Levallois-Perret, France, n° RCS 330 814 732 , [e-mail](https://www.lagardere-tr.com/en/contact-the-communication-department), as Data Controller in accordance with the Regulation.

**2\. Types of personal data processed**

No registration is required to access the site. However, there are sections on the Site that require registration and use of username and password, or services for which it is necessary to provide your data (eg. to contact us and be contacted).

If the Company acquires information and personal data, it will inform the users, from time to time, of the purposes for which these data are requested and of the ways in which they will be associated. Where necessary, the Company will acquire the user's specific consent to the relative use of the data. An example, used to request personal data such as name and surname, telephone number, e-mail control and other information that you accept and agree to provide to use the site's services by filling in a specific registration form. The Company registered the personal data collected online only for the purposes indicated at the registration site.

Uniform resource identifier URI of the requested resources, sent by the request, method used in submitting the request to the server, the size of the file found in response, the numeric code indicates the status of the data response from the server (successful, error, etc.) and other parameters relating to the operating system and the user's computer environment) are collected for the sole purpose of obtaining anonymous statistical information on the use of the site and to check correct operation and are deleted immediately after the user. The data could be used to ascertain responsibility in the event of hypothetical computer crimes against the Site: with the exclusion of this possibility, the data will be deleted after the time necessary for providing the services illustrated on the Site.

With reference to data relating to navigation within the Site, see also point 7 below regarding the Profiling Tools assigned by the Site.

**3\. Purpose and legal basis of the processing**

The data is collected and processed for the purposes strictly related to the use of the Site and its services. The purposes of using the data are indicated in detail in the specific information provided by the Site in all cases of data collection. We therefore ask you to read the information from time to time to illustrate the characteristics of the treatments that will be carried out by the Company (eg. To send requests through the "Contacts" section).

Your data will be processed:

\- according to art. 6, paragraph 1, lett. b) of the Regulations for managing the use of the Services requested through the Website and responding to your requests;

\- based on your consent, in accordance with art. 6, paragraph 1, lett. a) of the Regulations, to carry out marketing and analysis of your preferences.

In any case, the processing will be carried out in compliance with the provisions of the Regulation and the regulations in force - and their subsequent modifications and / or additions - issued by the Guarantor for the Protection of Personal Data (including Loyalty card and recommendations for consumers). rules of the Guarantor for the loyalty programs of February 24, 2005 and Guidelines on promotional activity and contrast to the spam of July 4, 2013, as well as the general provision regarding cookies Identification of the simplified procedures for the information and the acquisition of consent for the use of cookies on 8 May 2014).

**4\. Optional supply of personal data**

The provision of personal data is generally optional. Only in certain cases, failure to provide data may make it impossible to access specific services and obtain what may have been requested (eg to present your eventual candidacy); failure to provide such data may therefore prevent the Company from allowing access to the services of the Site or responding to users' requests.

The data from time to time necessary are precisely identified in the data collection forms present on the Website. By asterisk (\*) - the consequences of their failure to provide them are reported in the specific information on the data collection pages.

**5\. Data processing methods and scope of communication**

The data will be processed electronically. The Company provided the legal treatment and the correctness of the personal data provided through the Site, in full compliance with the current legislation, as well as the maximum confidentiality of the data provided at the time of registration.

The data will not be disclosed and will be processed by Company personnel expressly authorized to manage the Site.

For specific organizational and functional requirements, the Company has appointed a number of service providers related to the management of the Site as external managers for the processing of users' personal data. A complete list of external data processors can be requested by contacting [email](https://www.lagardere-tr.com/en/contact-the-communication-department).

**6\. Links to other sites**

This information is provided only for the Website www.lagardere-tr.com and not for other websites that may be consulted by the user via links. The Company cannot be held responsible for the personal data provided by users to external subjects or to any websites linked to this Site.

**7\. "Profiling" and / or customization tools**

The Company does not carry out any promotional and / or advertising communication activity without the user's prior consent.

The Site uses "cookies", both technical (ie to facilitate navigation and use of the Site), and analytics of third parties (to collect information on the use of the Site by users in order to process statistical analysis on an aggregate basis).

For a detailed explanation on the cookies used by the Site and how to disable them, please read our Cookie Policy.

**8\. Place of data processing and transfers outside the European Union**

The processing operations connected to the services provided by the Site are carried out at the Company's registered office, in Paris.

The data collected and processed through the Site will be transferred to countries outside the European Union, such as the USA, within the limits of the use of third-party cookies. In this regard, please refer to the Cookie Policy.

**9\. Data retention period**

Your data will be processed for the times specified in the specific information provided at the time of collection (eg "Work with us", use of the contact service). Your data, collected through the "Contacts" section of the Site will be processed for the time necessary to correctly manage your request and subsequently deleted. The data collected through the "Work with us" section and the creation of your candidate profile will be kept for 12 months after their insertion, after which they will be deleted. The data processed in the context of the @ -invoicing service will be processed for the entire duration of your registration for the service and in compliance with the terms of the law in tax and accounting matters (with reference to the data processed for billing purposes).

The data processed in order to send you communications about our products and services, offers and initiatives will be kept until your consent is revoked. If your consent is withdrawn, the data will no longer be processed for marketing purposes.

As regards the storage times of the data detected through the use of cookies, see our Cookie Policy.

**10\. Rights of interested parties**

To be sent to Lagardère Travel Retail SAS with a single shareholder, with registered office in 3/9 avenue André Malraux, 92300 Levallois-Perret, France , n° RCS 330 814 732 , [e-mail](https://www.lagardere-tr.com/en/contact-the-communication-department), you may at any time exercise your rights pursuant to articles from 15 to 22 of the Regulation that recognize specific rights including:

\- obtain confirmation that your personal data is being processed or not;

\- gain access to your personal data and to the information indicated in art. 15 of the Regulation;

\- obtain the correction of inaccurate personal data concerning you without unjustified delay or the integration of incomplete personal data;

\- obtain the cancellation of the personal data concerning you without unjustified delay;

\- obtain the limitation of the processing of personal data concerning you;

\- be informed of any adjustments or cancellations or limitations of the processing carried out in relation to the personal data concerning you;

\- receive your personal data in a structured format, commonly used and readable by an automatic device;

\- object at any time, for reasons connected with your particular situation, to the processing of personal data concerning you.

In particular, his right to revoke the consent to any processing provided and to oppose our analysis activities remains in particular.

**11\. Who can contact to make a complaint?**

We remind you that, if you believe that your treatment violates the provisions of the Regulation, you can always file a complaint with the authority for the protection of personal data (www.cnil.fr), or, if different, with the authority Guarantor of the country in which he habitually resides, he works or, finally, of the place where the alleged violation occurred.

**12\. The Data Protection Officer**

The Data Protection Officer designated pursuant to art. 37 of the Regulations by the Company can be contacted at the [e-mail](https://www.lagardere-tr.com/en/contact-the-data-protection-officer) address.

**13\. Applicable law**

This Privacy Policy is governed by EU Regulation 679/2016 which guarantees that the processing of personal data is carried out in compliance with fundamental rights and freedoms, as well as the dignity of the data subject, with particular reference to confidentiality, personal identity and the right to the protection of personal data.

**14\. Review clause**

The Company reserves the right to revise, modify or simply update, in whole or in part, in its sole discretion, in any way and / or at any time, without notice, this Privacy Policy also in consideration of changes in the law or regulation on the protection of personal data. Changes and updates to the Privacy Policy will be notified to users by publication on the Home Page of the Site, and will be binding as soon as they are published and communicated. We therefore ask you to regularly access this section to verify the publication of the most recent and updated Privacy Policy.

The full text of EU Regulation 679/2016 can be consulted on the website of the Guarantor for the Protection of Personal Data [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/FR/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32016R0679](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/FR/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32016R0679)

 Worldwide

Follow us

© 2024 Lagardère Travel Retail, a division of the [Lagardère group](http://www.lagardere.com/). All rights reserved. [Terms of use](https://www.lagardere-tr.com/en/terms-of-use "Terms of use") - [Privacy Policy](https://www.lagardere-tr.com/en/privacy-policy) - [Cookies](https://www.lagardere-tr.com/en/cookies)
